{
    "id": "37e8d03d8ae3438d8b58eebb7c2f40b1",
    "title": "Subordinating Conjunction Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "9bb31d08901b4b3089dadf67374fdaa5",
            "title": "Subordinating Conjunctions Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "……………………. she was ill, I went without her.",
                    "description": "As gives the reason. For is a coordinating conjunction. It cannot start a sentence. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "As",
                        "If",
                        "For"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I said nothing ………………………… he was angry.",
                    "description": "Because shows the reason.",
                    "answers": [
                        "as if",
                        "because",
                        "though"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "You won’t lose weight ………………………… you cut down on fatty foods.",
                    "description": "Unless means if not. You won't lose weight if you do not cut down on fatty foods. Or You won't lose weight unless you cut down on fatty foods.",
                    "answers": [
                        "if",
                        "unless",
                        "in case"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "He smiled ………………………….. he knew everything.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "as if",
                        "as though",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "……………………………. it was late, we decided to go out.",
                    "description": "Though is used to connect two contrasting ideas.",
                    "answers": [
                        "As",
                        "Though",
                        "Since"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I will go …………………………. you forbid me.",
                    "description": "Even if refers to present or future. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "even if",
                        "if",
                        "even",
                        "even though"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "………………………… you were playing, she was studying for her exam.",
                    "description": "Either when or while is possible here.",
                    "answers": [
                        "While",
                        "Since",
                        "When"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "The birds flew away ………………………… the hunter raised his gun.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "as soon as",
                        "as long as",
                        "no sooner"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "You can stay with me ……………………….. you take care of your expenses.",
                    "description": "Either as long as or if is possible here.",
                    "answers": [
                        "as soon as",
                        "as long as",
                        "if"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "………………………. they fought bravely, they could not beat the enemy.",
                    "description": "Though is used to connect two contrasting ideas. Even if refers to future.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Though",
                        "As",
                        "Even if"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "………………………….. had I reached home, ………………………… trouble started brewing.",
                    "description": "The correct expression is hardly...when...",
                    "answers": [
                        "Hardly, when",
                        "No sooner, when",
                        "Hardly, than"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "……………………………… you needed help, you could call me.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "If",
                        "Whether",
                        "Unless"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}